CHARLES VERLEYEN

Passionate about solving problems through data. Google Cloud is my playground. I like to act on the full spectrum of the data journey (from business workshops, design architecture and then implementation). I strive to bridge development with deployment and therefore I like to wear a SRE hat (I am experienced in DevOps, DataOps and SecOps).



CONTACT

charles.xavier.verleyen@gmail.com

+32 497 20 16 60

Val des seigneurs 67, 1150, Brussels

charlesverleyen.com

Charles Verleyen

SKILLS

Programming

Python

Bash **Javascript**

HTML/CSS

Operating Systems

Linux

Windows

Software & Tools

Google Cloud

Data Ingestion

(Dataflow - Apache Beam, Cloud Functions, Cloud Run, Pub/Sub, ...)

Transformation

(BigQuery, SQL, pandas, numpy ...)

Visualisation

(Data Studio, Looker, PowerBI)

Devops

(Terraform, Github, Gitlab CI, Spinnaker)

Kubernetes

Docker

Office

Business

Agile Project Management

Supply Chain Management

Corporate Finance

Accounting

Languages

French **Spanish English**

GOOGLE CLOUD

- Associate Cloud Engineer
- **Professional Data Engineer**
- **Professional Cloud Architect**
- Professional Cloud Security Engineer
- Professional Cloud Developer

WORK HISTORY

🛗 Jul 2020 - Present

Devoteam - Brussels

m Jan 2019 - Jul 2020

Devoteam - Brussels

m Dec 2017 - Dec 2018

Devoteam - Brussels

Jul 2015 - Feb 2017

Q CTA group - Antwerp

m Feb 2015 - Jul 2015

Lucky Cement - DR Congo

m Jan 2014 - Jan 2015

m

Dec 2012 - Dec 2013 General Electric - Mexico **Head of Data Analytics**

Google Cloud Lead architect

Google Cloud Data Engineer

Sourcing Manager & BI analyst

Project Manager

Procurement Manager & BI analyst

Supplier Quality Engineer

EDUCATION

Sep 2017 - Nov 2017

Data Science Retreat, Berlin

Mar 2017 - Jun 2017

♥ DevLeague, Honolulu

Sep 2006 - Jun 2012

Bootcamp in Data science

Bootcamp in Web Development

Louvain School of Management, Belgium BSc and MSc in Business Engineering

GENERAL SOFT SKILLS

Hard worker Rigorous Team Player Pragmatic Perseverance Pedagogic Business acumen Self-learning Simplicity

ACHIEVEMENTS, HOBBIES & INTEREST

- APICS CPIM certificate (5 modules achived). Obtained in September 2012
- ▼ Vice President of a renowned Junior Enterprise during my studies
- Various volunteer experience in Africa
- Sports enthusiast with active practice of Tennis and Swimming
- ➡ Holder of "PADI Open Water Diver Certificate" and "PADI Advanced Open. Water Certificate"

MY IDEAL DAY

